

HEMANT BALI

Application Project Manager And Scrum Master

LinkedIn Current Address: Kalkaji, New Delhi 110019 Mobile: +91 7011809119 +91 8527119122 Email: hemantbali96@gmail.com

Professional Summary

4+ years of experience, in IT Project Management with a solid understanding of business-oriented project element and SDLC. Educational and practical experience developing workflow solutions to meet client requirements actively while improving internal efficiency. Excellent delegation and leadership skills, including the ability to augment project team when necessary to meet budgetary requirements and deliverable schedules.

To secure a challenging position that would allow me to contribute my resourceful experience and personal skills for continuous growth and success of the Organisation

Skills

- ❖ Processes : SCRUM, Agile, SAFe, Blended Agile & waterfall methodologies
- ❖ Documentation: BRD, SRS, Test Cases Process Flows, SDLC
- * Tools: JIRA/AgileCraft, Swagger, Postman, FileZila, Gitlab, bitbucket, Git, S3 Bucket
- ❖ IT Skills : Microsoft Office, JIRA
- Soft Skills: Team player, Quick adaptability, Time management, Dedication
- Trainings: Project Management Training, Conceptual Design Thinking
- PowerBi Reports(Basic), Tableau(Basic)



Career

Fourbrick Technology Jan 2019-Current (2.4 Years)

Designation: Project Manager

Key Functions: Capacity & Resource Planning, Performance Management, Preparing Project Budget, Client management,

Business Plans

Fourbrick Technology May 2018-Jan2019 (8 Months)

Designation: Business Analyst

Key Functions Creating documents like, BRD, SRS, FRS proposals etc, Relationship Building, working with Data Analysis,

Supporting to Project managers

AHP Telecom Feb 2017- April 2018(1.3 years)

Designation: Project management -Associate

Key Functions Preparing Documentation, Overseas Client communication, getting daily updates with team, Project coordination.



Key Responsibilities

- Project planning, execution, monitoring/control, and closure of Mobile/Web Projects Artificial Intelligence products and Enterprise solutions.
- Handling Client communication and ensuring client satisfaction.
- Experience in managing "Change Requests" and prioritization in a fast changing environment.
- Ensure that projects are completed with the highest quality, on time and within scope. Also, Participating in creating documents like BRDs, SRSs, FRSs, Client Proposals, NDAs, Feature list, Capacity & Resource Planning and Budget Planning
- * Handling designing teams for Mock-ups, Wireframes and Prototyping of projects for demonstrating projects to client
- Tracking project status & daily status with the team (UI/UX Designers, Developers, DevOps Engineer, Testers, Data Science)
- Making performance improvement plans and processes
- Manage all post-delivery project needs including Confirming project closure with key stakeholders, Sharing invoices, handover the development along with KT and assuring client satisfaction.
- Familiar with App indexing, Deep linking, App store optimisation, Attribution, interactive push notifications, user segmentation and targeting, etc.
- Participating in Technical Audits and sharing reports.
- Handling DevOps team for giving Approving for access to developers and designer for Repositories. Merge approval for master branch, after reviewing with leads. (Gitlab, Bitbucket, Git)
- Raising Invoices & clearances from clients after successful approval on Milestones
- * Taking Managerial rounds for New teammates and coordinating with Hiring team

Project History

> Tamimi Markets (E-commerce Platform)

Saudi Arabia, Utility app

Platform: Web, Mobile app (Android and iOS) & Admin panel Duration: 8 Months Team Size: 14+

Project Description: Tamimi Markets is a well-known ecommerce platform (supermarket chain) with 30+ active stores in Saudi, for edible products. Frontend is based on AngularJS and backend developed on NodeJS. Integrations involves Loyalty system, payment gateway, Firebase, Mailing system and MongoDB (Database). Artificial Intelligence Conversational chatbot for Customer care, order status and feedback processing.

Responsibilities involves working for business objectives & tracked progress to ensure project milestones were completed on time, on budget & with desired results. Addressed problems through risk management and contingency planning.

➤ MPE Tool (Client: AT&T)

Dallas, USA Enterprise Solution

Platform: Admin Panel and Android App Duration: 6 Months Team Size: 6+

Project Description: AT&T Inc, an American based company, looking for an Enterprise level tool for operating submission done by field engineer, followed by report maker, Quality assurance, co-ordinator and SME. This tool automates the submission of telecom projects details and process it with respective department. Responsibilities involves working for business objectives & tracked progress to ensure project milestones were completed on time, on budget & with desired results.

Addressed problems through risk management and contingency planning.



> Oyo Rooms (Rental property app)

Guraon, India Utility app

Platform: Admin Panel and Android App Duration: 6 Months Team Size: 6+

Project Description: Oyo Hotels & Homes, is an Indian Hospitality chain of leased and franchised hotels, homes and living space. Required to build an application for renting home space, connecting with appropriate buyers/database and managing the activities from admin panel.

Emmar & Al Fares (3D Runner Game)

Dubai, UAE Game

Platform: Admin Panel and Android App Duration: 6 Months Team Size: 8+

Project Description: 3d game consist of 60 different levels with 3 stages for Users. It discovers Dubai landmarks, deserts and beaches. Facebook Integration and Subscription bases membership, play store storyboard etc. Consist a team of Unity developers, 3d Designers, Asset makers, backend developer and testers.

Other projects include: Taxi app, Defect Analysis System, HRMS, Car rental app.

Education

Bachelor of Commerce (Hons)

Delhi University New Delhi (Shri Guru Tegh Bahadur Khalsa College) 2015-2018

Awards/Certifications

- Excellence Award for RISING STAR in Fourbrick Technology in the first year of service
- * Excellence PRINCE @, CAPM, ACP- (On Going)